Taimoor Ahmad

Software Developer

Street No 6, New Islam Pura, Toba Tek Singh +923049389777 taimoorahmad139@gmail.com@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a dedicated person who wants to use his skills and get exposure to the learning environment and want to be part of the success and excellence. As a graduate with 3+ years of experience in IT. I am an energetic, ambitious, and self-motivated person who has developed a mature and responsible approach to any task that I undertake, or situation that I am presented with. My professional goal is to become a valuable asset and productive member of a company. I am excellent at working with others to achieve a certain objective on time.

SKILLS

• PHP • Laravel • React JS • MySQL • Git • Docker • Elasticsearch • Python

EXPERIENCE

Inspire Uplift, Faisalabad - Software Developer

April 2019 - May 2022

- I Work as a Software Developer.
- Develop software using Php and its frameworks.

Wampdo Software Solutions, Faisalabad - Internee

January 2019 - March 2019

- Internship of 3 Months.
- Learn how to implement Python in Real Life Projects.

EDUCATION

COMSATS University Islamabad, Sahiwal Campus - BSC(Software Engineering)

September 2014 - July 2018

Superior College, Toba Tek Singh - FSC(Pre Engineering)

September 2012 - July 2014

National School System, Toba Tek Singh - Matriculation

March 2010 - July 2012

PROJECTS

Inspire Uplift

Create integrations with Magento, Shopify, woo commerce, Wix.

Create modules unit/feature tests.

Create REST Apis for the front-end.

Create algorithms for Boughttogether products recommendation and trending Products.

Bakery ERP

http://raheemsw.com/admin/public/

It is a Bakery point of sale and management system. It has several Modules like Sale, Purchase, Inventory, Ledgers, Income Reports, Employees management Etc. It is created using Laravel. There are several other projects like this with the addition of different modules. These projects are

1. Rice Trading

URL: https://razaprinters.com/custom/public

2. Peshawar Traders

URL: https://razaprinters.com/peshawer/public

Construction ERP

It is a point of sale project. It has multiple modules like Purchase, Sale, Inventory, Income reports, ledgers, Attendances Etc. It is created using Laravel.

Solar Market Egypt

It is an implementation of an online store for solar systems using Laravel. It has 3 users Customer, moderator, and Admin. Admin has access to the whole system, while moderator has access to backend with limited functionality like creating products etc. The customer has access to the front-end only. The site has also blog functionality within.

URL: https://design.solarmarketegypt.com

Commish

It is an implementation of an accounts system for a loan company using Php/Laravel. It allows users to create/manage functionalities related to loan systems like providing loans to customers and calculating commission for the broker and other parties involved in the process. Other than that it has reports like profit/loss, commissions etc.

URL: https://commish.mkhurram.online/v2/public

• Invoice Generator

It is an implementation of an invoice generator using Php/Laravel. It allows users to enter details of invoice data into the form and It will generate invoices according to the given data with auto calculations like taxes, VAT, etc. User can re-generate the same invoice whenever he/she wants as data getting stored in DB.

• Property Management System

It is a Property Management System developed using PHP programming language. It has Multiple modules like Employees Management, Property Sale/Purchase, Rent Building/Apartments on installments Etc.

School Management System

It is a School Management System implemented in Laravel. It has multiple modules like Student management, Attendance module, etc.

SCLSV Limousine Service

It is a backend system for sclsv limousine services. It allows drivers to submit their daily travel history with other details like requirements of cars etc. It also allows users to generate data in form of CSV. Only admin can generate other users' data but others only generate their own data.

• Email Scheduler

It is an implementation of a scheduler using Php. It sends email to specify customers of an online store who order 3 days ago and 10 days ago from current date. It fetches emails from that specific dates and sends emails using SendGrid which is also implemented using Php.